Guide to the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace pamphlet and microfilm collection, 1817-1950 MS2110
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Unbound pamphlets, 1817-1950; MS2110 Series 2; 47 Linear feet
  - "The League of Nations", 1930 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-12, Author:Buell, Raymond Leslie; Foreign Policy Association no. 61
  - "The League, the Far East and Ourselves", 1934 ca. (Box 6, Folder 40)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-13, Author:Bulwer-Lytton, Victor Alexander George Robert
  - "Lessons from the History of the League of Nations on Security and Disarmament", 1948 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-14, Author:Carnegie Endowment for International Peace; typescript
  - "Disarmament and the League of Nations", 1923 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-15, Author:Cecil, Lord Robert; Foreign Policy Association no. 17
  - "League of Nations - An Address", 1918 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-16, Author:Cecil, Lord Robert
  - "Shall We Commit Suicide?", 1924 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-17, Author:Churchill, Winston S.
  - "Is the Versailles Treaty Responsible?", 1936 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-18, Author:Cohen, Bernard Lande
  - "That Seven Million Plurality", 1936 ca. (Box 6, Folder 46)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-19, Author:Colcord, Samuel
  - "The League of Nations and Freedom of the Seas", 1918 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-20, Author:Corbett, Julian
  - "The Future of the League of Nations", 1934 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-21, Author:Coudert, Frederick R.
  - "Revision of the League", 1934 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-22, Author:Coudert, Frederick
  - "An Analysis of the Issues Presented by President Wilson's Appeal...", 1920 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-22, Author:bCravath, Paul D.
  - "A League of Nations - A Challenge to the God of War", 1919 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-23, Author:Dean, Benjamin S.
  - "The Aims of the League of Nations", 1929 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-24, Author:Drummond, James Eric
  - "The Senate and the League of Nations", 1920 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-25, Author:Eliot, Charles W.
  - "What the League has Done: 1920-1936" (Box 6, Folder 54)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-26, Author:Fanshawe, Maurice and MacartNew York (N.Y.) C.A.
  - "Research Activities of the League of Nations", 1929 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-27, Author:Feis, Herbert
  - "Organizing Peace", 1926-1933 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-28, Author:Garnett, Maxwell 3 editions
  - "The League of Nations - The Opportunity of the Church", 1919 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-29, Author:Gore, Charles
  - "Some Reflections on the League of Nations as Related to the History of the United States", 1918 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-30, Author:Graham, Samuel J.
  - "New Fabian Research Bureau - The Prevention of War or Labour and the League of Nations", 1930 ca. (Box 6, Folder 59)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-31, Author:Greaves, H.R.G.
  - "The League - Its Weakness and A Possible Remedy", 1935 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-32, Author:Green, Jerome D.
  - "Woodrow Wilson and the League of Nations", 1926 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-33, Author:Gregory, T.W.
  - "The League of Nations", 1918 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-34, Author:Grey, Viscount
  - "A Governed World Through a League of Nations", 1918 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-35, Author:Gulick, SidNew York (N.Y.)L.
  - "Geneva 1930" (Box 6, Folder 65)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-36, Author:Harris, H. Wilson
  - "Geneva (Switzerland) 1931" (Box 6, Folder 66)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-37, Author:Harris, H. Wilson
  - "Hoover Says Without a League of Nations to Guide New Republics Europe Will Go Back to Chaos", 1919 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-38, Author:Hoover, Herbert
  - "The Way Out", 1919 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-39, Author:Houten, Dr. S. Van
  - "Reservations to the Covenant of the League of Nations", 1919 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-40, Author:Hughes, Charles Evans
  - "The Preparation of the American Delegates to the Peace Conference", 1918 (Box 6, Folder 70)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-41, Author:Hyde, Charles Cheney
  - "World Opinion and the League", 1934 (Box 6, Folder 71)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-42, Author:International Federation of League of Nations Societies
  - "Germany and the League", 1927 (Box 6, Folder 72)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-43, Author:Jackh, Ernst
  - "America and The League of Nations", 1919 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-44, Author:Kahn, Otto H.
  - "An International Banker's View of the League of Nations", 1923 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-45, Author:Kahn, Otto H.
  - "The Separation of the Covenant of the League of Nations from the Peace Treaties", 1937 ca. (Box 6, Folder 75)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-46, Author:Kelsen, Hans
  - "Some Legal Questions of the Peace Conference", 1919 (Box 6, Folder 76)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-47, Author:Lansing, Robert
  - "Bulletin of Sweet Briar College: Democracy, the League, and Wilson - A Prophecy", 1935 (Box 6, Folder 77)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-48, Author:Laukhuff, Perry
  - "Contributions to the Foundation of a World Democracy", 1919 ca. (Box 6, Folder 78)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-49, Author:League of Nations
  - "The Covenant of the League of Nations", 1936 (Box 6, Folder 79)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-50, Author:League of Nations Association
  - "Essential Facts in Regard to the League of Nations, the World Court, and the International Labor Organization", 1938 (Box 6, Folder 80)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-51, Author:The League of Nations Association
  - "Fourteen Fallacies about the League Refuted", 1933 (Box 6, Folder 81)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-52, Author:The League of Nations Association
  - "List of Publications", 1931 (Box 6, Folder 82)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-53, Author:League of Nations Association
  - "List of Publications", 1933 (Box 6, Folder 83)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-54, Author:League of Nations Association
  - [Publications], 1924 ca. (Box 6, Folder 84)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-55, Author:League of Nations Association
  - "A Short History of the League of Nations", 1929 (Box 6, Folder 85)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-56, Author:League of Nations Association
  - "Statement on Reorganization of the League of Nations", 1936 (Box 6, Folder 86)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-57, Author:The League of Nations Association
  - "Suggested Program for a Model League Assembly", 1935 (Box 6, Folder 87)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-58, Author:League of Nations Association
  - "Teaching Plan on the League of Nations for Use in High School Classes in Modern History", 1931 (Box 6, Folder 88)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-59, Author:League of Nations Association
  - "World Peace Procedure Bolivia - Paraguay", 1929 (Box 6, Folder 89)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-60, Author:League of Nations Association
  - "Student's Movement in Japan for the League of Nations", 1925 (Box 6, Folder 90)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-61, Author:League of Nations Association of Japan
  - "The Assembly at a Glance - 1934" (Box 6, Folder 91)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-62, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "The Backwoodsmen", 1931 (Box 6, Folder 92)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-63, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "Canvasser's Answers to Objections Concerning the League of Nations", 1934 ca. (Box 6, Folder 93)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-64, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "The Children's Crusade", 1934 ca. (Box 6, Folder 94)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-65, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "The Christian Church and the League of Nations", 1935 (Box 6, Folder 95)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-66, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "Draft Pact for: The Future International Authority with Commentary", 1944 (Box 6, Folder 96)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-67, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "The League Carries On", 1941 (Box 6, Folder 97)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-68, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "The League's Critics Answered", 1934 (Box 6, Folder 98)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-69, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "The League of Nations and China", 1919 (Box 6, Folder 99)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-70, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "The League and the Drug Traffic", 1934 (Box 6, Folder 100 item 1)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-71, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "The League and The Colored Races", 1932 (Box 6, Folder 100 item 2)
  - "Arms and the People", (1932) (Box 6, Folder 100 item 3)
  - "The League and Human Welfare", 1933-1939 (Box 6, Folder 101)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-72, Author:League of Nations Union; (3 editions)
  - "Proceedings of the Conferences of Delegates of Allied Societies for a League of Nations", 1919 (Box 6, Folder 102)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-73, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "Refugees and the League", 1935 (Box 6, Folder 103)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-74, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "50 Facts and Figures About the League of Nations", 1933 (Box 6, Folder 104)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-75, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "Some Familiar Objections Answered", 1933 (Box 6, Folder 105)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-76, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "Treaty Revision and the Covenant of the League of Nations", 1933 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-77, Author:League of Nations Union
  - Various Pamphlets, 1923-1929 (Box 6, Folder 107)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-78, Author:League of Nations Union
  - Various Pamphlets, 1931-1941 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-79, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "What Are the People Thinking", 1929 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-80, Author:The League of Nations
  - "What Does the League Cost?", 1932 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-81, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "Yearbooks - 1933 & 1934" (Box 7, Folder 4)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-82, Author:League of Nations Union
  - "Yearbook - 1936" (Box 7, Folder 5)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-83, Author:League of Nations Union
  - Miscellaneous League of Nations Pamphlets, 1918 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-84, Author:League To Enforce Peace
  - "The Lodge-Lowell Debate", 1919 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-85, Author:Lodge, HeNew York Cabot and A. Lawrence Lowell
  - "The League of Nations and the Coal Problem", 1935 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-86, Author:MacartNew York (N.Y.) C.A.
  - "The World Dream", 1931 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-87, Author:May, Herbert A.
  - "The Treaty of Versailles and Other Peace Treaties of the Era Napoleon-Bismarck", 1921 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-88, Author:Mette, Dr. S.
  - "The League of Nations", 1920 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-89, Author:Miller, David H.
  - "The League of Nations and the Democratic Idea", 1918 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-90, Author:Murray, Gilbert
  - "The Peace Terms", 1919 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-91, Author:National Peace Council
  - "President Wilson's Fourteen Points of Settlement and What They Mean", 1918 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-92, Author:National Peace Council
  - "The Wilson Peace Terms", 1920 ca. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-93, Author:National Peace Council
  - "League of Nations Gains Favor in Latin America", 1931 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-94, Author:Nerval, Gaston (news clip)
  - "Coudenhove - Kalergi: Plan for a Reform of the League of Nations", 1933 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-96, Author:Pan-European Union
  - "The Filing System of the Secretariat of the League of Nations", 1945 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-97, Author:Pastuhova, Catherine
  - "Complete Text of the League of Nations Covenant", 1925 ca. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-98, Author:Pearson, Barney
  - "Economic Consultative Committee of the League of Nations", 1929 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-99, Author:Pipkin, Charles W.
  - "The League of Nations and International Commerce", 1928 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-100, Author:Pipkin, Charles W.
  - "The Revision of Treaties", 1933 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-101, Author:Polish Institute for Collaboration with Foreign Countries
  - "The League of Nations - An Historical Argument", 1918 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-102, Author:Pollard, A.F.
  - "The League of Nations and Collective Security", 1936 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-103, Author:PonsoNew York (N.Y.) Arthur
  - "The Covenant of The League of Nations", 1927 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-104, Author:Potter, Pitman B.
  - "The Idea of a League of Nations", 1919 ca. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-105, Author:The Research Committee of the League of Nations Union
  - "The Way to the League of Nations", 1919 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-106, Author:The Research Committee of the League of Nations Union
  - "Notes on the League of Nations", 1935 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-107, Author:Richards, Henry
  - "The League of Nations in 1937" (Box 7, Folder 29)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-108, Author:Rolin, Henri and HeNew York (N.Y.)A. Atkinson
  - "Letter of Elihu Root on Revised Draft Proposed Covenant of League of Nations", 1919 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-109, Author:Root, Elihu
  - "The League of Nations", 1944 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-110, Author:Schuette, Oswald F.
  - "The Aims and Organization of the League of Nations", 1929 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-111, Author:Secretariat of the League of Nations, The
  - "Fabian Tract No. 226: The League of Nations", 1929 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-112, Author:Shaw, Bernard
  - "Text of the Draft Treaty of Disarmament and Security, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-113, Author:Shotwell, James T.
  - "Where Minds Meet", 1939 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-114, Author:Shotwell, James T.; Foreign Policy Association no. 28
  - "The League of Nations: A Proposed Constitution Designed to Insure Peace", 1936 ca. (Box 7, Folder 36)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-115, Author:Smiley, James L.
  - "The Future of the League of Nations", 1938 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-116, Author:Smuts, Jan and Avenol, M. Joseph
  - "The League of Nations; A Practical Suggestion", 1918 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-117, Author:Smuts, J.C.
  - "The Relationship Between the Assembly and the Council of the League of Nations", 1930 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-118, Author:Spencer, Richard Carleton
  - "May the United Stated Join the Proposed League of Nations by an Exercise of the Treaty-Making Power?", 1919 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-119, Author:Stafford, Wendell, Phillips
  - "Hague (Netherlands) Conference: The ONew York (N.Y.)Existing All-Including League of Nations", 1915 ca. (Box 7, Folder 41)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-120, Author:Stead, Francis Herbert
  - "Essays on Berman and the League", 1927 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-121, Author:Stesmann, Gustav
  - "A League of Nations", 1919 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-122, Author:Stuart, Graham H.
  - "Draft of a Constitution of the Universal League of Nations", 1919 ca. (Box 7, Folder 44)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-123, Author:Swiss Committee for the Preparation of the League of Nations
  - "In the League and Out", 1930 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-124, Author:Thomas, Norman; Foreign Policy Association no. 63
  - "Open Letter" [League of Nations], 1916 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-125, Author:Trevelyan, Charles Philips
  - "Collaboration Between the League of Nations and Non-Member States", 1939 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-126, Author:U.S. Department of State
  - "The League of Nations: History, Development and Failures", 1949 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-127, Author:U.S. Department of State; typescript
  - "Letters of the Hon. Elihu Root Relative to the League of Nations", 1919 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-128, Author:U.S. Senate
  - "Confessions of a Pro-Leaguer", 1929 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-129, Author:Verne Oggel, Melvin
  - "The Future of the League of Nations", 1920 ca. (Box 7, Folder 51)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-130, Author:Walston, Charles
  - "The League of Nations", 1931 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-131, Author:Watt, Raymond G.
  - "The League of Nations", 1933 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-132, Author:Watt, Raymond G.
  - "What the World Owes President Wilson", 1930 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    World War I and the League of Nations Pamphlets: Previous folder number: B-1-133, Author:Webster, Charles Kingsley
  - "Geneva (Switzerland) 1933 - An Account of the Fourteenth Assembly of the League of Nations" (Box 7, Folder 55)